Now we're covering an introduction to
stakeholder management.
So although we're covering
this last, this is one of
the most important knowledge
areas that we'll discuss.
We need to figure out who our stakeholders
are.
Who's going to be impacted by our project?
Who's going to impact us?
Who's going to make decisions?
How do we effectively engage them?
set expectations, manage their
expectations.
How do we get them to support our project?
So that's what the stakeholder knowledge
area is all about.
Figuring out who's going to be impacted by
our project, who will impact us,
and how do we get them to support our
project and project decisions.
Okay.
So this is about building relationships
with the stakeholders.
engaging them appropriately to support our
project.
Alright, so if you're following along in
your PIMBOC, you're on page 503, 503.
All right, so let's go through our slides.
We're identifying all individuals,
groups, or organizations.
That could be departments within the
organizations as well, that can impact our
project, and out of them who will impact
us.
All right.
and this is positively or negatively so
let's say we're consolidating all our
offices that are spread out around the
world down the street okay we're going to
build a new facility all right so we've
got 15,000 people that are impacted by our
project they're going to have to move okay
out of those 15,000 people.
Who are our key stakeholders?
Who's going to impact us?
Who's going to be making the decisions?
Who do we report to?
Who's going to have the resources?
For example, all right?
So we will identify our stakeholders
throughout the project.
In the very beginning, as in initiating
process group, as we're developing our
project charter, you start identifying
your stakeholders you at least know two
stakeholders in that project charter you
because that's where you are formally
named and your sponsor or initiator all
right they are in the charter along with
any other high level key stakeholders you
already know about next we have to
identify their potential impact on our
project who has influence power who has
interest in our project okay we have to
develop the appropriate management
strategies to effectively engage the
stakeholders again appropriately not
everybody has to be engaged the same all
right um this is considered the most
important success factor on a project
successfully appropriately engaging our
stakeholders communicating with them,
having them on our projects, meetings,
whatever the case is.
It's our job to get them to support our
project.
Remember, most people don't like change.
Our project creates a unique product,
service, process, result.
So it means change.
So we've got to get them on our side to
support the project.
All right, that's what this whole
knowledge area is about stakeholder
management, figuring out who's going to be
impacted, who's going to impact us,
impact our project, and figuring out the
best way to engage our stakeholders,
to effectively and efficiently get the
stakeholders to support our project.
That's usually by communicating with them,
again, involving them in our project.